Md. Estiak Ahmmed

Software Engineer

Road: #22, House: #149,

Mohakhali Dohs Mohakhali, Dhaka,

Po: 1207 Bangladesh

Mobile: (+880) 1739948408 Email: merin.ruet09@gmail.com

Profile

I am a Software Engineer. I am good with javascript (frontend: React js, Redux, Next js, Mobile: React Native, Backend: Node js) and I'm also comfortable with php, Wordpress. I have basic knowledge about Golang, Django, ROR, Python, Java and I can work with this stack too. I have a bachelor degree under Computer Science & Engineering department, I was a Competitive Problem solver, Solved many Algorithm, Data Structure, Complex Mathematical problems. After Completing my graduation in early 2014 Started my professional career as a Full Stack developer. I have worked with many projects with Remote & Local company. I've built lots of applications in terms of complex UI/UX or large scale based app Professionally with a team or individual basis.

I like to solve Programming Challenges, Passionate about making New Things.

EXPERIENCE

UOUAPPS, Switzerland - Web developer

january 2014 - august 2015

I worked with php, Wordpress, Node js Related application, I have got my professional experience to work on a production app and learned how to deploy an app in the production server. I have also worked as a lead technical support agent. I have developed many Wordpress Theme, Plugins and Large scale based ecommerce application.

Redqteam - Software Engineer (Full stack developer)

august 2014

I am one of the core developer of this team. Here i Mainly work as a Full stack developer. I got most of my professional experience as a full stack developer working with Readteam. I've worked with Api development, Database schema design, complex UI/UX challenges, app data management, technical support, searching system etc. In

Fronted I have Mainly worked with javascript, React, Redux, Redux Saga, Apollo, Next js. In Backend I have worked with Node js, Express, Graphql, Firebase, Firestore, Google cloud function, AWS Lambda, S3, Php & Go, Docker, Kubernetes.

Rivetly, Canada - Full stack developer

May 2018 - August 2018

I have worked with an Employee Management system and helped them to created their Reward App Program for their Employees. Node Js, Firebase, Google Cloud Function, React, Redux, Redux Saga, Ant Design Stack have been used in this project.

InterBit - BlockChain Convention Test Writer using Redux, Redux Saga September 2018 - November 2018

I was a part of Interbit Convention Testing Program. Where a set of Test Specification for Interbit Core Module was tasked by the Senior Dev to complete using Redux, Redux Saga & Interbit Test Harness

EDUCATION

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology, Rajshahi - B.Sc (computer science department)

MONTH 2009 - MONTH 2014.

AWARDS

- Hold the 10th place of National Programming contest (NCPC) 2014,
- Runners up of Inter University programming contest (IUPC) 2012.
- Regional Champion of Rajshahi District in International collegiate Programming contest (ICPC) 2012.

SKILLS

- Back-end Web: WordPress, Php, Nodejs, Express, Graphql, AWS Lambda,
 S3, Google Cloud Functions
- Front-end Web: JavaScript [ES6], React Js, Redux, Redux Saga, Reflux,
 Angular 1.x, Next Js, Apollo
- Mobile: React Native
- Data Stores: MySQL, Firebase, Firestore, Redis, Mongodb, Postgresql, S3
- Test: mocha, enzyme, chai, karma
- Development tools: Git, Gulp, Webpack
- API: Facebook, Twitter , Google , Dropbox, ycombinator, Stripe, Github, Youtube, Algolia, auth0 etc
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes,

ONLINE PROFILE

- [upwork] http://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/_~01e6a8adf290ab0556/
- [Github] https://github.com/merin83
- [SO] http://stackoverflow.com/users/4697189/md-estiak-ahmmed
- [Linkedin] https://bd.linkedin.com/in/md-estiak-ahmmed-48698b98

WORKS

- 1. https://isomorphic.redg.io/
- 2. https://mate.redg.io/?v=1.3
- 3. http://reactive.redg.io/
- 4. https://wordpress.org/plugins/reuse-builder/
- 4. https://rivetlyprototype.firebaseapp.com/